AARON JOHNSON

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER



347.786.0266



aaron@ajfs.me



www.ajfs.me



Greater NYC Area

ABOUT ME

A multi-disciplinary pixel-perefectionist with a love for clean code, I bring a wealth of diverse experience to the table enabling me to hit the ground running on entry. I particularly excel in high-stakes environments where my contributions are essential toward both team and org KPIs.

EXPERIENCE

INTERACTIVE DESIGNER

POST STUDIOS 2019 - 2020

- Mockup design for digital interactive ad campaigns using Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator & XD.
- Using HTML, CSS & JavaScript, I craft engaging interactive experiences for both web & mobile.

CREATIVE MANAGER

TREMOR VIDEO 2014 - 2018

- Distributed pre-production mockup & post-sale production requests to various members of the design team, offering design guidance as needed.
- Collaborated with sales and ad ops depts. in educating clientele as to our product offering, platform capabilities & performance metrics.
- Supplied additional support for maximum transparency surrounding campaign goals and outcomes.

DESIGNER

TREMOR VIDEO 2013 - 2014

- Designed and built custom advertising experiences using Photoshop, ActionScript & JavaScript.
- Handled all levels of development, from animation to interaction to custom reporting exposure.

RELATED PROFICIENCIES

HTML NODE

CSS PYTHON

JAVASCRIPT POSTGRES

REACT / REDUX GIT

PROJECTS

WORLD CORONAVIRUS MAP - REACT, MAPBOX GL, ARCGIS API, TWITTER API

- An interactive map that tracks the latest infection counts and rates as supplied by the ArcGIS database.
- Map also provides recovery/death counts and rates per selected state or country.
- Users have access to real-time tweets from individuals in the affected areas that are accessed via Twitter's Statuses API.

AJ'S CONWAY GAME OF LIFE - REACT, LESS

- Interactive visualization of Conway's game of life, a well-known computational algorithm that makes use of an easy-to-follow deterministic pattern in which selected cells on a grid move through the "life"/"death" cycle via a preconfigured set of parameters.
- End-user may view an animation of this pattern by pre-selecting their own patterns on the grid, or by generating a randomized start pattern.
- Additional UI features grant users further control over the animation cycle.

GITHUB USER LOOKUP - REACT, LESS

- GitHub user search engine that returns known GitHub users by handle.
- \bullet Typically returns a result, whether or not a known user is inputted.

EDUCATION

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT Lambda School

2019 - 2020

Continuing web development education, focusing on current technologies and best practices. Technologies include React.js for frontend development, Node.js (backend), Python (CS theory, data structures & algorithms) as well as Knex & PostgreSQL for query-building and database management.

A.S., DIGITAL MEDIA COMMUNICATIONS KATHARINE GIBBS SCHOOL

2004 - 2006

Web major, focusing on design theory and and application through practical development. Acquired knowledge of Adobe CS, HTML, CSS & ActionScript. Graduated in the top 10 percentile.